[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-radio.net
sc radio is brought to you by the ieee
computer society by ieee software
magazine online at computer.org software
hello everyone welcome to this episode
of software engineering radio our guest
today is gail hoffer gill is the
co-founder and cto at salto salto is
pioneering the building of tools for the
business engineer to control visibility
into their business applications in a
way similar to how devops revolutionized
it
in the past gil has been a vp
engineering at oracle and vp rnd at
ravello systems welcome to the show gail
so happy to have you here is there
anything you'd like to add to your bio
before we start no thank you kancha it's
really great to be here i'm excited to
talk with you about the interesting
things that we're doing at salto so
salto is pioneering the building of
tools for the business engineer
i know the developer we all know the it
engineer and more recently the devops
engineer nsre who is the business
engineer that's a great question kanchan
so
as you know today any modern business
uses a very large collection of business
applications in order to render
businesses
applications like salesforce for the
sales processes or netsuite for finance
or zendesk for support in any
organization you would see anything
between a few tens to a few hundreds of
those now the thing is that in order for
for the organizations to actually use
these business applications
they need first of all to configure
customize or extend or develop to those
business applications so they'll fit
their internal processes it's something
that they do when they're on board but
also continuously over time as the
processes change
now
someone needs to be tasked with actually
managing those business applications
understanding exactly what's going on
there and keep on evolving and managing
and administrating those
these are the business engineers they
take pride at managing those business
applications
they need methodologies they need tools
and they are a really important part of
any modern business today
in many cases they will still go by some
other names you will got your salesforce
administrators you will have your
netsuite developers you would have your
zendesk administrators and one of the
things that we're realizing today in the
industry is that
we need to create
a real home a real category for these
engineers so they will take pride in
what they're doing they will have the
right tooling and methodologies and will
be able to build a real function very
similar to what we saw with the devops
just 10 15 years ago
because of course salesforce calls it
salesforce administrator but if i'm a
salesforce administrator i'm also doing
netsuite administration as well and
perhaps a zillion other things so i'm
way more than a
salesforce administrator i am the
business engineer is your point
in many cases you will deal with
multiple business applications
but even if you deal just with with
salesforce let's say yourself first
developer architect or
administrator your day-to-day is
partially in the domain of managing
sulfur for managing revenue or sales
processes
but it also has a lot of more technical
bits
how do you make sure that
those things that you develop are the
same things that you roll from your
sandbox to your production how do you
walk as
a team and review each other's walk
how do you make sure that you clean up
tech debt which keeps on accumulating in
your implementation
all of those concerns these are actually
cross-cutting concerns which are not
specific to sulfurs and they're part of
the practice for proper engineering
practice
and this is part of what we're preaching
here today
and the thing is that it is applicable
across all different business
applications it doesn't really matter if
you're managing
sulfurs or netsuite or zendesk or
oracle fusion
eventually in your day to day the types
of activities and challenges that you're
dealing with which are coming also from
more of an engineering type of
challenges they're all very similar they
deserve similar
tools and methodologies
again very similar to the way that
things eventually evolved with
software development and devops and we
should talk about that the evolution of
just software developer tools and devops
but
how did the business engineer persona
come to be
is this fairly recent
yeah so we're seeing that
in many organizations today you would
see a growing organization in many cases
titled the business applications
organization in some cases some
organizations would call it an
information systems in some cases it
would be still distributed across
different uh business units
but what we saw is that
as companies
onboarded more and more sas business
applications as part of them
having a best of breed strategy we saw
that those teams kept on growing and in
some organizations we're seeing teams of
tens and hundreds of people
who are tasked in their day-to-day with
managing those business applications
as more and more resources go to those
areas both in terms of
administrators but also managers and
obviously budgets we're seeing more and
more focus in those organizations on
those areas
which in turn
leads
a focus on
being more efficient having the right
methodologies in place when you walk and
these are the
fundamentals which eventually an entire
discipline such as business engineering
is starting from so it is very recent
we're seeing it in the past few years or
so from the organizations which are
leading the camp
and are
much more advanced in the way that
they're managing their business
applications but
judging from the past and other things
also evolved with devops or with test
automation or with infrastructure is
code
usually these become much more
widespread as time passes because
the rest of the industry realizes that
it is
an efficient
and productive way to go to
so let's kick off with the history of
the tooling for developers
if we can just walk through the
evolution
maybe then we can draw some parallels
with devops and then the business
engineer sure i can try i've been
around the industry just for the past
20 years but i think that we need to
look
much further into the past because
people have been trying to program
computers
from the 40s give or take right and
we're seeing that
in the late 50s early 60s i've been
trying to
find better ways to collaborate in teams
and that's actually if i remember
correctly in 1962
first version of a source control system
right because
development teams wanted to see how can
they make sure that they can collaborate
multiple human beings together on the
same code base
it doesn't matter that eventually the
code base translated into punch cards or
into other types of media but the
logical problem was how do we
collaborate in a team and how do we keep
track of the changes that we do over
time because they matter
so
starting from the 60s we kept on seeing
methodologies being built on top of
tools
if it was for source control later on we
saw
bug tracking software we saw
testing started with how do we manage
our manual testing
switch
went into
automated tests of of various types and
then i think
the main change started in
the mid 90s give or take back then
the title was the the software crisis
right
why can't we produce
high quality software why we keep on
having projects which never end on time
and we have quality issues etc
and
the
human nature usually is to try and add
more processes more visibility
the dreadful waterfall processes right
from the 80s and 90s
and then at the end of the 90s
with
the adrenaline manifest on the entire
agile movement i think that the entire
industry realized that
there are much better ways to do that by
utilizing
first of all common sense
but also much better tooling and
processes
hands-on
agile the reliance on automated testing
in many cases
fast forward a little bit into
automating everything around deployment
around configuration management around
testing and monitoring
i think it's interesting to see how
in that relation to development also i.t
evolved over the past 20 years or so
because i think that the piles they're
also very very interesting if you go
back
not that long ago let's say 15 years
into the past then
many it persons would start the day
literally holding a box
doesn't matter if it was a virtual
server or physical server
then going into the data center putting
that box into a rack
opening an installation guide and start
typing
and it would take them half a day to a
day to install a new server with
the latest version of software that they
had to install on it
and then it was
pretty much a rinse and repeat process
and
obviously it wasn't scalable it wasn't
something that
high-performing high-skill organizations
could really could really deal with
and
luckily enough these were exactly the
same days when
we started to have apis in front of
everything it started with
virtualization with vmware and
virtualization of compute and later on
of networking and storage and obviously
went to the extreme with
aws with amazon web services in the
public cloud which put
every compute network and storage
resource at the tip of our fingers with
an api call
and what happened back then is that
the real high performing organizations
they realize that
they can actually
bypass their at and provision those kind
of resources
and on the way also
import all the best practices that they
used to know from
development into the world of i.t under
infrastructure all of a sudden
if the definition of
an instance on ec2 or server in in the
cloud
became a source file in source control
that you conversion
that you can take a design pattern from
another company let's say someone has
the best definition of
a redis cluster
it is encapsulated now in code so all of
a sudden
that
50 years of advances in software
development
was
almost overnight applied to
infrastructure
and all of those methodologies around
how do we make sure that whatever that
we just developed in
our development environment is the same
that we deployed to our production
which was always applied to code
now becomes exactly the same for
infrastructure
how do we make sure that the team can
review changes down to the
infrastructure
exactly the same thing that was done to
code
was all of a sudden applied to
infrastructure
and then this entire notion of
started with configuration management
let's say with tools such as chef puppet
and later on with ansible salt etc which
obviously went to the extreme with tools
such as
terraform or pulumi which
build themselves on infrastructure is
code right
but if we pause for a second at the core
of it it is all around
importing those
60 years already of best practices and
tools from software development into the
world of i.t and devops and making
things
much more
predictable
and repeatable
and visible
because think about it for a second 20
years ago
in order to answer the question of
what is it that you have
in your inventory in the data center
you would have to open a database you
would have to open some highly curated
list or run all kind of discovery tools
in order to populate
back then all the rage was around and
cmdb creating a database of your
configuration
well today
that infrastructure that you have in
your
highly virtual data center in the cloud
it is actually what you have described
in your telephone code which is
exact sitting in the exact same git
repository next to your application code
and everything became
more predictable and streamlined
and
if we pause for a second to think
then
actually the things that we're seeing
with business applications configuration
which are being managed in a relatively
manual air dock way directly in
production
it has a striking similarity
to what it has described about 18 15
years ago
that same
i.t person going into the data center
with the box
it's not that different from your
network administrators going into your
production instance and clicking a bunch
of different buttons in the ui in order
to implement whatever configuration then
that's needed
same problems around visibility and
predictability and and scale and being
able to walk in a team
and well i'm an engineer so usually if
you see
a certain pattern of problems emerging
i would
usually opt in for trying and use the
same tools or ideas to solve them and
as we started as we said
it is all about adopting
engineering best practices and tools and
methodologies
also in the field of business
engineering and business applications
thanks girl for the history
yeah it was very interesting so the
things that i got from
kind of divide into two or three
sections
one is the setup and deployment is more
predictable and repeatable those are the
two words i get that makes sense and
then you mention visible
what exactly do you mean by visible
sure so i'll answer it both around
software and infrastructure as well as
for business applications for business
applications actually it is a very
simple explanation
i can actually share an anecdote from a
customer of ours last week
anonymous but this is a very large
zendesk customer and as part of the
setup in zendesk you define what is
called
a trigger a trigger basically whenever
something happens in the system then it
triggers another action
now
that company which is a very big company
actually has a setup with
different triggers in their zendesk
instance now
obviously
there is some kind of dependency also
between the order of the different
triggers because if something runs it
can actually trigger another trigger by
the action that he just did
now it is a great example because it is
very similar with in all the other
business applications but in order for
them to actually know what is it that
they have implemented right now
the only way for them to do that is to
log into zendesk
they got a huge list of triggers
and
they need to either click on them one by
one or remember by the name of the
trigger what is it that it is doing
so obviously at this scale they cannot
do that so they actually maintain a huge
spreadsheet
on the side which describes exactly what
is each and every trigger what is it
good for what is it doing why did we
build that
and they need to maintain that list up
to date now
this is absurd
because all of that information is
actually encoded in that system
and
the way that we're thinking about these
kind of problems in saltor is well
we connect to that system to zendesk in
this case and we extract all of that
information into
into code now what is code basically
code is
a language which human beings can read
and also has structure so a computer can
also read and understand that
so once i extract all of those triggers
into code
you can all of a sudden
search them
for certain
strings and traits
and even better you because there is
structure it is code you can actually
very easily answer questions like
what are all the triggers which get
triggered by a change in that field this
is something which can be very very
almost impossibly hard to answer in most
of these business applications because
all of that knowledge is really hidden
behind
endless number of ui screens
and by extracting all of that logic into
code which is searchable and is
structured
all of a sudden
it is like we're
literally lifting
a veil
and enabling those administrators all of
a sudden
to understand
what is that they have already
implemented in their system
and
this is one of the really
fun parts of my week
is to go on
a first meeting with the customer
they connect your system for the first
time they fetch the data into salto
and then
you hit those like this
huge smile on their faces
because all of that information that
is hidden and scattered in so many
places
become visible
it is similar to
i can remember the first time that i
think i was
12 back then the first time that i
searched something online there was no
google i think it was alta vista or
excite one of those ones so the first
time that you realized that
you have
all that information at the tip of your
fingers
and think about it that for those
administrators in many cases they know
that it's implemented but they have no
way to actually know what is it that
they have implemented
it is very similar to a developer
working on a code base
and having just
bits of that code base in in source form
and the rest
in binary form
it's a really hard thing to do
and in many cases that's how they're
working to get today so creating
visibility
is
at least from our point of view it's
always the first step later on we can
use this visibility in order to
create much
better teamwork and the proper
change management process for example
when you actually go and change that
configuration but the first step is
always well
you have to be aware of what is that you
have implemented right which is
surprisingly hard in many of those cases
today in those business applications
so
predictable repeatable for the changes
you're making the configurations you're
doing
visible is
what do you get from the framework what
do you get from the configurations
themselves
yeah in the framework you're using
and we'll talk later a little bit more
on how you choose which ones to make
visible etc
but the other thing you mentioned also
was working in a team so collaboration
tools
so are those the categories
setting up offer the code deployment
making visible and then collaboration
generally there are i think that if we
go back to engineering
there is some intersection between the
different tools meaning
take a look at git for example and the
source control tools then
they are very important for
collaboration
because that's part of your way to
think of a pull request for example to
ask for a coil review and for other team
members to review or walk
they're also very important for
revision history and making sure that
you actually know what changes over time
in your code base
ides for example are very important in
order for you to develop code but
they're also great
code understanding and visibility tools
if you need to understand what
finding references of certain code parts
etc so
the activities that you mentioned are
correct these are all activities which
are basically part of
the application
life cycle management the the sdlc right
which we all know by hard to say that
whenever we develop a new feature or
product
it starts with a planning phase which
parts of it is a requirement that
designed and we actually
implement and test and we maintain
etc the same activities are basically
also happening
when you walk on the configuration of
the business applications
just that unfortunately today you're
lacking tools that's what we're trying
to to help with
so the one category of tools we did not
really talk much about was related to
observability
monitoring
i'm guessing your you know
business engineers would rely on
the actual applications that they're
using to take care of that piece is that
fair
in many cases yes what we're seeing
that in many cases business engineers
would also
stream a lot of data to a data warehouse
and in those cases
they would run
reports on top of the data warehouse in
order to make sure that their data is is
still correct because
in most cases monitoring would tie to
data correctness with business
applications
now there are some cases
where you actually extend the
functionality of a business application
then you might actually break some flow
and
some users would start getting errors in
the ui
the native tools would usually alert
from those if you have got a broken flow
on salesforce then you'll get an alert
if
there's a broken screen on netsuite you
would usually get an alert but i agree
that there are there are some gaps there
i think that
it is a very interesting area to explore
especially on the relations between
the business outcomes because eventually
those business applications
they're all tied to business processes
right you've got your quote to cash
process which is involving multiple
different business applications
and
i think that monitoring those kind of
processes also which
go across different business
applications and understand
how they perform on the business level
which is
really the holy grail in observability
of what we're talking here
is
an
area which is not really being served
today
and
i think that it can be an interesting
one in the future
so
talk now about the evolution of business
apps
one of my questions to you earlier was
why now you know what's new about the
business engineer and your response was
that a trigger for creation of this role
has been because customers have moved to
adoption of best of breed so multiple
applications
as the on-premise to sas move influenced
this as well in any fee
i think you're right i think that the
on-premise to sas
is one of the enablers for the
best-of-breed approach
because
when organizations were mostly
on-premise
the overhead of
managing another business application
even just from a pure operational
standpoint
of installing it on a server and
monitoring and keeping track with
patches
and upgrading and backuping
the tax that you had to pay for each
additional business application that you
installed on-prem was very high so you
really had to choose
what are the applications that you're
using and in many cases you will have to
resort to a best-of-class sales solution
and not a best-of-breed
now because of the move to the cloud
the
cost of all of these underlying
operational tasks became almost
non-existent because these are things
that the sas providers the software the
service provider is taken care of so the
actual cost of onboarding
another solution became much lower and
that's one of the reasons that we're
seeing so many business applications in
modern organizations
which on the other hand creates a real
problem on how do you how do you
actually manage those at scale
so the setup has certainly dramatically
changed
how has the customization and
administration needs changed with move
to sas
so
the thing is that
because
those applications
are
relatively
targeted and narrowed in some cases in
what they're doing
then they're also highly customizable
and they allow for features which in the
past in many cases
required
proper development effort
and what we're seeing that with the rise
of sas business applications which go
ending end with
no code and low code tooling
they are also highly customizable
and they empower the administrators
to really
implement
many many use cases that in the past
really require the development results
the flip side of this by the way is
that it helps with the actual
first development
but as we all know
development is just the first step in a
much longer journey of of a feature or
system which
maintenance is a very big part of it
and over time
as the maintenance cost becomes
much more dominating compared to the
original development cost
and there is maintenance because you
need to keep on changing your processes
and you have
a lot of tech depth already in whatever
that you have implemented now it doesn't
matter that you've built it with clicks
and drag and drops instead of writing
code
logically you still have tech up there
you have all kind of different fields
and processes that
god knows what are they doing
and
because
they relied on no code or local tooling
in order to build that
they don't have
proper tooling for the maintenance part
and compare it to code where we have it
figured out right because we rely on
code so you know it is that you have
implemented you can change it you have
version history etc this is missing on
the maintenance part
so on the one hand those tools are
extremely powerful in terms of
customizing them
but they're still lacking in terms of
maintenance and
the later parts of the software
life cycle
as you were talking i realized that as a
developer you obviously will write
to some extent what you will implement
and before you actually implement it so
with low code or no code platforms
is that typical
or is a visibility really after you have
configured it
so
we do see that most organizations at
least at a certain scale
they do document
at least their business and
all the way to a functional spec more or
less
so
for example you would have a jira ticket
which would describe the change that you
would like to do from
functional or from a business point of
view
then you would usually go directly to
implementing it it's not that
some developers
for example originally would start like
building a skeleton with some comments
and then start replacing those with
functions
you don't really have the tools to do
that in many cases in those business
applications whether you would go and
implement directly
now
one of the things that as a software
developer always used to love doing is
to keep traceability between
that change that they just did
to that business requirement for example
to that jira ticket
and
technically the way that you would
usually do that as a developer would be
through the source control system right
you have your
commit into git you would annotate it
correctly so it would get picked up by
jira
so then you've got full traceability you
can look at the business requirements
understand exactly what is it that
you've changed in the code and vice
versa
unfortunately with business applications
you don't really have a way to do that
again because you don't have code you
have that missing link in between
and i can share that with quite a few of
our customers that's actually the first
use case that they start with because
they want to make sure that they have
this traceability between a business
requirement an actual change in their
configuration
so they will be able to go in either way
and one of the things that salter
enables them to do is basically to have
a code representation of their
configuration that then they can tie
back into a git commit which gets tied
back into a jira ticket for example
yeah that sounds really really
fundamental
how many sas applications are typical
for a medium-sized company's back office
systems
so
in recent service you would see numbers
ranging from
anything from
200 to 800 those ranges
now obviously not all of those sas
applications have the same weight right
it's not that
you've got your let's say your main erp
can be an oracle fusion or sap or
netsuite it doesn't have the same weight
as tooling for a sales developer
representative
so if we look at the real major tools
then usually you would see anything
between 10 to 20 and that wallpark with
a few per department you would have a
major a main tool for the sales
department for example salesforce and if
you go a level deeper then for example
the
sales development or business
development would have their own main
tools such as outreach
you would have a main tool for the
marketing department such as hubspot or
marketo
for the support department such as
zendesk for finance such as netsuite
so this accumulate each one of those
that i just mentioned they are really
deep tools with a lot of configuration
with usually a team or multiple teams
which manage
jira for example which is a very
centralized tool for development
organizations
in large companies you will have large
teams which manage it
with so many there's obviously
integration needs as well there's salt
to help with that
so
salto it does and it doesn't and i'll
explain many of the integration needs
are actually around
run time
data exchange between these tools
whenever you change a field in
jira you want to automatically update
something on
zendesk because it's a bug which relates
to a customer that we're communicating
with
so we're not there in runtime
but
a big part of the problem is
how do you know what are the different
fields that you actually need to
synchronize and how do you know that
that field in zendesk is actually
dependent on
that other field in jira
we do help with that with being able to
understand to understand the data flow
more of a design time understanding but
we're not there at runtime
we do help companies in
the fact that
they have now a
single unified streamlined process
to manage the configuration of those
business applications we're helping them
with that
if you look at integration
there are some really great modern tools
for the business engineers
such as a workato for example or
trey io and there are a lot of other
tools out there which help with the
actual runtime data synchronization
problems
what did people
do
if they're not using tools like salto
what have they done so far
so obviously
companies walk and they found their own
ways in some cases
[Music]
they
choose not to do certain changes so it
has a an impact on the business
i can share a personal story
salto is not our first company of me and
my co-founders we actually had another
company before called ruvelo systems
which was a sas company we're actually
an
a cloud provider
and back then
in some areas we actually chose not to
do certain changes on the business side
because
we understood that actually implementing
them on our business application stack
would be too costly
so we actually chose not to do certain
changes because we knew that it would be
too hard for us to implement them
companies obviously
when things are very important to them
they will do that
it usually translates to
more resources so teams with growing
size growing budgets
a lot of reliance on consultants
and a lot of hard work
in some of our customers
in some of those business applications
you don't really have a way to
just copy changes from your sandbox your
production account
extremely basic i know but in some of
those business applications there's no
way to do that
and we're actually working with a
customer
who has 20 different production
instances
and they have a team
which manually logs into 20 different
production instances
and push the same buttons over and over
again
because they don't have a way to
automate it obviously the business needs
to operate so they do that
they're not happy about it it is slow it
is
labor intensive and it is error prone
because you might miss a click
but that's the way that they work today
so you had an example where
you said hey this is too hard to do i'm
going to fail i just won't do it
is there also a story you said
the business impact is way too high i
need to do this and then you found a way
or really suffered is there anything
like that you can share
yeah
so in ravello then we got acquired by
oracle actually
and one of the first things that we had
to do was to
integrate ravelo's back office into
oracle so
sounds like a relatively simple task
right you basically need to introduce
a few skews a few catalog numbers into
the oracle
cpq is the term right it's the quoting
system
now
obviously we had to do that right we had
to enable the field to sell ravelo
it was a very very long and manual and
tedious process
many many calls with tens of people
to make sure that
the exact data is being deployed from
dev to integration to uat to production
multiple approval cycles a process which
took many months and
took us a lot not just us also all of
our peers at oracle
but obviously you have to do that now
that was one of
the realization moments for us that this
needs to happen differently because when
we manage
software or infrastructure devops id
we found ways
to make it
much more
streamlined repeatable
and
almost effortless
in those parts of their release cycle
and there is
really no reason not to do that for the
business applications
and there's no need to
really struggle with that because the
pain back then
it was hard
so it was not repeatable which is why
you had to test
at each step along the way
that was
the downside which yeah
we had to
test on each way on the way also the
different environments they were not
identical
so in some cases by definition
you had to do some changes
to what you deployed to
integration versus the actual content
that you deployed to uat versus the
actual content that you deploy to
production
so
it's not just that you don't have a
button which deploys and you need to
repeat it you actually need to do
slightly different things at every stage
and because of that
you really do want to have multiple
people review those changes
because you do want to minimize the
chances of a human error and
making a mistake there can be very
costly because the field would
sell the wrong products right that's
like core business
of the company
so it was
non-repeatable
in
various aspects right not just the way
that
you cannot
just click a button or run a script and
deploy but also that you need to
actually deploy different things to
different environments
there's lots of dependencies yeah
so your solution salto solution if i
read the website and you've talked about
this is translate the business
applications configuration into text
allowing you to search compare deploy
and track changes across the
environments
how do you choose
which
configurations to do this for because
clearly there is work per type of
configuration
yeah so
when we connect to a new business
application in salto today we support
seven
main business applications
so when we connect to new business
applications we first of all map
the configuration space
to understand what are the relevant or
important configuration types
in many cases we need to differentiate
between what is metadata versus what is
data or what is configuration versus
what is data and then we focus on
configuration only
now over time we've built infrastructure
on our side which allows us to actually
add many more types with a very very low
effort
for example many modern apis today would
have a swagger spec or
i think we're supposed to call it the
open api 3 today
so when an api has a spec then we can
just connect to it directly
and almost
generate the rest of the parts on our
site which can connect to that api
and in many cases the question of
what would you like to manage as
configuration it is also a logical
question for users
because you would get cases where
certain
data elements for example
are actually configuration from their
point of view think of an erp system
like netsuite or oracle fusion
so in some cases the definition of
subsidiaries
in some organizations which would
actually treat that as configuration
that they would like to go through the
different gates and release cycles etc
well this is actually data in those
systems so we also enable our customers
to
tell us well
in the system also treat that data as
configuration or
suppress that configuration it is
irrelevant
so
when we started salto for the first two
or three adapters we actually did it by
hand we just
wrote the code to support
all the different metadata types or
types that we had to support in those
systems and then we generalized and the
next
for adapters for using that
infrastructure just allows us to pick
and choose much more easily
what about other vendors and solutions
in this space
great question so
i think it can be interesting to look at
two types of other vendors and solutions
i think the first one is vendors who are
targeted at the infrastructure domain
and i think the main one to look there
is
obviously hashicorp with a telephone
because
the core concepts of terraform which by
the way we love telephone we use it
ourselves in order to run our own
infrastructure
but terraform is basically doing very
similar things
to
infrastructure and platform as a service
in some cases there are some core
differences between what we're doing and
what they're doing
but
at the core id it is relatively similar
they're focused on infrastructure we'll
focus on sas
and business applications and we think
there's more than enough for multiple
vendors in in those areas
another type of competition of vendors
which are in the ecosystem are vendors
which are targeted at a specific
business application and at the specific
use case
for example if we look at a salesforce
for example so there are multiple
vendors who are trying to solve problems
with
sulfur's devops or change management
within devops with vendors such as a
copado or gearset
about five or six different main players
were targeted at that area
or if you look at netsuite and
compliance
so there are there's a vendor there a
strong point
i think that the difference here is that
those vendors they all came from
a specific need in a specific business
application
and they developed the best solution for
that specific need
our approach is different we came from
an
infrastructure point of view
that an organization needs an
infrastructure
to manage the configuration of all the
different business applications
and then we basically were building it
top down when we tackle a specific
business application
we add the capabilities so our solution
would be
at least as good as those vendors were
specific to to that business application
and that specific use case in that
specific business application but we
also cater and solve for a lot of other
use cases within a single business
application but also across all of them
so different approaches to the problem
so i listened to this episode i have a
lot of parallels in my job you know i
feel i'm a business engineer how do i
keep up with this topic
that's a great question and one of the
main
challenges that we want to take on
ourselves looking forward in the next
few years
is to start and build a real community
around business engineers because
we're seeing that they're lacking in
many cases
the ability to go and talk with appeal
in another company and understand what
are the
industry best practices for business
engineering that this is something that
we're going to deal with extensively
until then my recommendation would be to
find your peer group go to user groups
understand what are the best practices
in your field there today
we write about this quite a lot in our
blog by the way so
you can follow it or follow
myself or some of my or my co-founders
on linkedin and and twitter we do try
and
lead
some of the thoughts on those areas
but my number one tip would be to
start and
consider yourself
as an engineer
meaning that
engineers in many cases they're very
scientific methodological persons take
pride in what they do
we cannot continue and manage
those business applications we're saying
the focus is on the business side and
the administration is
whatever needs to be done in order for
us to do that because it is not
sustainable so
take pride in your walk
try and understand why things are
working the way that they are
when you see and that's very common for
engineers when you see a process which
is not optimal
try and optimize it ask why are we doing
that manually
keep on
optimizing the processes
that's the first step towards becoming a
great business engineer
we'd certainly love to have the link to
your blog or any other links in our show
notes
all right great anything we missed that
you would like to cover today
no i think it was a very interesting uh
discussion at least for me i hope that
also for you kanjan yeah i think we
covered it all yeah just it's really was
interesting again i certainly feel this
is a topic that is going to grow
and certainly interested in
keeping in touch and
how can people contact you and be in
touch with you
definitely so
i'm
most active on linkedin so
feel free to connect send messages i'm
also active on twitter so that's also a
good venue
and for salto
one of the interesting things is that
we also have a very active open source
project which basically implements what
they just described so
you can download it and just use it free
fully functional and
try and become a
better business engineer
we also have a free tier of our product
which can be used free for life no
strings attached it's not a free trial
it's a free for life
so that's also a great way to keep in
touch of what is it that we're doing at
salto definitely we'll include some of
these links in our show notes it's so
great to have you here today girl
i learned a lot i hope our listeners did
too thank you so much thank you so much
bye
thanks for listening to sc radio an
educational program brought to you by
ieee software magazine for more about
the podcast including other episodes
visit our website at se radio.net
to provide feedback you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on linkedin facebook twitter or through
our slack channel at scradio.slack.com
you can also email us at team
sc-radio.net
this and all other episodes of sc radio
is licensed under creative commons
license 2.5
thanks for listening